Translator
翻
ssnake
譯
ἐκκλησία
ἐκκλησία
From now on, the Soul Church will
現在魂召會開始
Timing
時 間 軸
zwc1991
zwc1991
απάθεια
απάθεια
όρκα
όρκα
hold an inquisition on the former apatheia corps commander, Orca.
就原傀儡軍團長 奧爾卡一案進行審問
φάλαινα
φάλαινα
Although we have to keep the sinners of Fallaina,
誠然我們必須避免 讓流放到大沙海的法萊那及其罪人
who has been exiled to the great sea of sand, from being found by
被蘇益德拉西亞聯合王國或其他國家發現
φάλαινα
φάλαινα
But Fallaina is in exile at the evil water.
但是 法萊那的流放海域乃是魔之海域
It should be extremely difficult to approach and even discover them.
發現並與之接觸應當是極為困難的
φάλαινα
φάλαινα
The annihilation of Fallaina,
法萊那的殲滅
was not an action that we have to take at this moment.
並非必須立刻執行的作戰
Who proposed and forced us to do that?
提案強行實施這一作戰的
It's you!
正是你
Indeed, the exile judged 93 years ago
而且說到底 93年前的流放
was a story for our citizens to take it as an example.
乃是面向國民以儆效尤的「故事」
By the story that the sinners revealed their emotions and conflicted ugly,
要以罪人們顯露出「感情」 互不相讓的醜樣
our citizens can recognize the foolishness of having emotions again.
讓國民再次認識到持有感情是何等愚蠢
And that's how you persuaded his Majesty as well as us.
你正是這樣說服我們和陛下的
However, your strategy
可是你的作戰卻
failed.
失敗了
At his Majesty's command,
皇帝陛下已經做出了決斷
απάθεια
απάθεια
όρκα
όρκα
apatheia corps commander Orca, the chief executive of this action,
對本次作戰的最高負責人 傀儡軍團長奧爾卡
σκύλος
σκύλος
αράχνη
αράχνη
Arakhne, the commander of skulax,
以及斯奇洛斯司令阿拉弗尼
as well as other hundreds of people are sentenced to death.
等百餘名處以死刑
Is that...
難道這…
the best story you may tell?
就是你們所謂最好的「故事」嗎？
What's wrong?
有什麼好笑的？
Excuse me.
不好意思
I just... thought it was a little shabby.
只是…覺得有點不太高明
What?
什麼？
Keep from responding to his provocation!
不可上他挑釁的當
Long long ago,
據說
The heaven cut a piece of its body,
上蒼曾經撕碎自己身體的一部分…
and gave it to the world it has once rejected.
將之下賜給了其一度拋棄的這個世界
Thanks to that, the old bad civilization had faced its death and rebirth.
由此 陳腐墮落的文明迎來了死與新生
καθαρτήριο
καθαρτήριο
That is the tale of the rain of purgatory
這就是 「煉獄之雨」的傳說
Then, what are we?
那麼 我們又是何等存在呢？
νοῦς
νοῦς
After the world had been cleaned up, we worshiped Nous, the body of heaven.
在世界被清洗乾淨之後 我們崇拜神的身體「魂形」
We got its power.
獲得其力量
νοῦς
νοῦς
And we determined to deposit our minds, the roots of our faults, with Nous.
決定將「心靈」這一過去諸惡之根源交給魂形保管
Then, we have two types of human beings in the world.
由此 世上誕生出了兩種人類
νοῦς
νοῦς
The evangelists of Nous, and those who can't be evangelists.
能成為魂形的使徒的人 和成不了的人
Evangelists are called Shirushi, and those who can't are Muin.
成得了的人被稱為「印」　而成不了的人則被稱為「無印」
Well, now let's talk about something you may have already forgotten.
接下來的…或許是大家已然淡忘了的事情
There are a third type of human beings.
曾經有第三種人類存在
The third...?
第三？
δαίμονας
δαίμονας
That's the Daímonas
…那就是「惡靈」
νοῦς
νοῦς
The ultimate warrior created by Nous with its power.
由魂形之力所創造的最強的戰士
δαίμονας
δαίμονας
Daímonas is just a rumor.
惡靈什麼的不過是傳說
That's how we forgot these, treating them as the bygones.
就這樣 我們將其作為過去的產物拋之腦後
But now we can't pretend as they are not existing.
但如今 我們不能再視而不見
σκύλος
σκύλος
φάλαινα
φάλαινα
The boy in Fallaina who destroyed Skulax,
破壞掉斯奇洛斯的法萊那的少年
δαίμονας
δαίμονας
he is exactly the Daímonas!
他正是惡靈
Let me redifine it here:
在此讓我重新定義
δαίμονας
δαίμονας
Daímonas is the threat that came back to our empire.
所謂「惡靈」 就是再度降臨帝國的威脅
They have the power to overturn our country, which should be an ark.
擁有能顛覆我國這一方舟的力量
They are the recognition of some terrible sins.
是值得畏懼的罪惡的具象化
After you have seen such an existence...
而在親眼目睹了這樣的存在之後…
αράχνη
αράχνη
Arakhne!
阿拉弗尼
How did you treat him?
你是怎麼對待他的？
According to the records, you despised and abused him.
根據記錄 你似乎輕視了那個人
I was...
我是…
I can't say you are innocent.
你可沒辦法說自己毫無過失
No, I can even say you are badly...
不如說 就罪過的嚴重性來說…
Shit!
該死！
No... no!
不 不是的！
Because Orca pulled his weapon...
是奧爾卡先掏出武器…
Weapon?
武器？
The records are full of blood...
記錄都沾滿血了…
Who had assigned missions to such a guy,
像這樣連控制感情都做不到的人
who can't even control his emotions?
又是誰給他安排任務的？
ἐκκλησία
魂召會
It's you!
是你們
Even you have never been to the battle field,
哪怕你們遠離戰場
νοῦς
νοῦς
don't forget it's your fault to have thee Nous sank.
也萬萬不可忘記讓魂形沉沒的責任
Now let's turn to the new chapter of our story.
那麼差不多該開啟故事的「新篇章」了吧
You say the new chapter?
你說「新篇章」？
It is quite possible that
在不遠的未來
καθαρτήριο
καθαρτήριο
a second rain of purgatory will fall in the near future.
存在降下「第2次煉獄之雨」的可能性
Don't change the topic!
你是想偷換話題嗎！
How dare you live without even a single sense of crisis!
…你們這些沒有危機感的人
This world can't be clean unless it is washed and cleaned again.
不再清洗一次的話 現今的世界是無法乾淨的
And at that time we must protect this country,
因此 我們必須要保護好屆時將成為「方舟」的這個國度
δαίμονας
δαίμονας
Daímonas should be controlled by our country.
惡靈必須要由 我們國家掌握
Why do you want to control the Daímonas?
你說要掌握惡靈？
φάλαινα
φάλαινα
We can just destroy it along with the Fallaina.
連法萊那一起消滅掉不就好了嗎？
Who can?
誰去？
δαίμονας
你讓誰去解決掉惡靈？
νοῦς
δαίμονας
Or you mean if the Daímonas sinks another Nous,
νοῦς
you will just execute those who involved?
你們就又把關聯的人處死
And make it as if nothing happened?
當作一切都沒發生過嗎？
Shut up!
你怎麼說話的！
Your brains are just like the ruins under the sea,
就用你們這些像沉沒海底的遺蹟那般！
badly corroded with rust!
生鏽了的腦袋！
Take your story of devastation!
繼續譜寫你們滅亡的故事去吧！
What can you do in this situation?
…你倒說說你能做到什麼
δαίμονας
δαίμονας
I will capture the Daímonas for you.
我會抓住惡靈
Only I can make it.
我的話是做得到的
δαίμονας
δαίμονας
Daímonas rewrited the theory of this world.
惡靈能夠改寫世間的法則
The presence of it will lead our country to the absolute hegemon of the world!
其存在能引領我國成為世界的絕對霸主
Isn't it?
難道不是嗎？
δαίμονας
δαίμονας
I did well until the discovery of Daímonas.
到發現惡靈為止 我們做得不錯
There is only one thing I have to regret.
值得遺憾的只有一件事
σκύλος
σκύλος
αράχνη
αράχνη
That is the arbitrariness of Arakhne the Skulax commander.
那就是斯奇洛斯司令阿拉弗尼的獨斷專行
What?
什…！
All right. We leave him to you.
好吧 收拾部下這種事就交給你自己了
Wait... Wait a minute!
等…等等
όρκα
όρκα
You dare! Orca!
你這傢伙！ 奧爾卡！
Orca!!!
奧爾卡——！
νοῦς
νοῦς
Heaven blesses the servants of Nous!
願上天保佑魂形的下僕
Excuse me?
打擾了
ατσάλι
ατσάλι
απάθεια
απάθεια
Dear Atsali, our current commander of apatheia corps
阿查理 現傀儡軍團長閣下
The finish of inquisition
雖說審問結束了
doesn't mean your failure has been canceled out.
但你的失策可沒有一筆勾銷
I understand.
當然了
But there is no point in pulling your leg.
但在您面前遮遮掩掩也沒什麼意義
Let me tell you straight away.
我就單刀直入地說了
καρχαρίας
καρχαρίας
Give me the battleship Karcharías.
請把戰艦卡魯哈利阿斯交給我
σκύλος
σκύλος
But you have just lost Skulax.
可是你剛剛才損失掉斯奇洛斯
If you agreed to give it to me, the church will accept.
只要長官答應讓給我 議會也會聽從的吧
What's up?
有什麼問題？
Do you remember the first time you talked with me?
我們第一次交談的時候說的那些 你還記得嗎？
I forgot.
忘掉了
You don't need to give it to me immediately.
您不必立刻做出決定
You can have some days to think it over.
您不妨先考慮幾天
I'm waiting for your good news.
靜候您的佳音
What were you talking about?
你們說了什麼？
Something about the dream.
夢話
You Shirushi have had a same dream?
「印」的大家都做了一樣的夢…？
Yes.
是的
In that dream, a girl entered our ears and sang a song.
少女進到耳朵裡面唱歌的夢
What did... it imply?
這個…到底是在暗示什麼呢
And after all, for us Muin who didn't have that dream,
而且我們這些沒有做夢的「無印」
it is difficult to get over it.
現在也完全領會不到情況
Don't worry!
沒關係的！
We understand it, I think.
大概 我們是知道的！
♪　ラララ…
♪　ラララ…
Lalala...
♪　啦啦啦…
♪　私たちを
♪　私たちを
Please find us
♪　茫茫沙海中
♪　見つけておくれ
♪　見つけておくれ
in the sea of sand
♪　請把我們找到
The mud whale is advancing!
泥鯨開始前進了…
Creatures are amazing.
生物是如此的不可思議
♪　泥の船で櫂を漕ぎ
♪　泥の船で櫂を漕ぎ
Rowing the paddles of the mud ship
♪　讓泥船兒盪起雙槳
Nobody has taught the star locusts,
誰也沒有教過星蝗
♪　白砂の褥で眠る
♪　白砂の褥で眠る
Sleeping in the white sand
♪　夜晚以白沙為床
but they can flicker in the same rhythm.
但它們卻能以一樣的節奏閃耀光芒
The migratory birds know where to go since they were born.
候鳥生來就知道自己要前往何方
We are the same.
我們也是一樣
♪　小さな旅人よ
♪　小さな旅人よ
Oh, the little traveler
♪　小小的旅行者啊
We have already known
我們 已經知道了
how to move the mud whale.
開動泥鯨的方法
♪　ただひとつになろうとしても
♪　ただひとつになろうとしても
Even we want be together
♪　哪怕想要與你化為一體
They move the ship with such a game...
用這種小遊戲來操作
After all, that is this island.
還真是 有這個島的風範呢
How glory it is when all the residents gathered together.
住民全員集合的話是這麼壯觀呢
♪　無限のちらばりにしかなれない
♪　無限のちらばりにしかなれない
we will be apart forever
♪　也只能散落成無限的飛沙
Roharito-sama.
羅哈里特大人
What?
嗯？
Have you noticed?
您注意到了嗎
The percentage of young is too high.
年輕人的比例太高了
Ya...
嗯…
What's wrong with you?
你沒什麼精神啊？
The dream is too strange?
那個夢太神奇了？
Or you are nervous about the guests?
還是說 在意那些客人？
I also worry about what I don't know.
我也會害怕不知道的東西的
But the coming of guests,
不過 有客人到來
κόκαλο
κόκαλο
the understanding of Kókkalo after the dream,
和從夢裡知道骨頭的真相
don't you think they mean we are connecting with somebody else?
總有種誰在跟我們連繫的感覺
We are really departing again.
這次 是真正再次出發了
Yes.
…是的呢
That's something only the Shirushi know.
只有「印」知道這種事
As a Muin, I feel a little lonely.
作為「無印」 多少有些寂寞呢
But now we can go wherever we want with the mud whale.
不過 這樣一來泥鯨就隨心所欲去往任何地方了
Wherever...
不論天涯海角…
Even where the empire's fang can't reach!
也包括帝國的爪牙伸不到的地方
Was there a plague in the island?
這個島上爆發過瘟疫什麼的嗎？
Or the adults died when the empire attacked you?
還是說 帝國襲擊的時候大人都死了？
As I told you before
就像以前說過的那樣
it's because Shirushi is short-lived.
因為「印」的壽命短
As a result, we seems to have too many young people.
結果上 看起來好像年輕人特別多
The soldiers of empire can use the same power as those on the island.
帝國的士兵能使用和這座島上的人一樣的力量
But I have never heard of other short-lived races.
但是 如此短命的種族 我從來沒聽說過別的
Who are you, the people of this island?
這座島上的民眾到底是什麼人？
I don't know.
不知道
You hiding monkey! You just don't wanna tell me!
你這裝傻的猴子！ 打算欺瞞寡人嗎！
I really don't know.
真的
If I know it,
要是我能知道為什麼
I don't need to make these herbal medicine for prolonging life!
就不會在這裡做延長壽命的草藥了！
Bring me to your room.
帶寡人去你房裡
Eh?
哎？
Be quick!
快點來！
I will show you the world.
讓你見識見識世界
This is the chart my ship used.
這是寡人的船上用的海圖
Cha...rt?
海…圖？
A map shows what the sea is like.
就是記錄海面狀況的地圖
I can't understand a single...
到底是怎麼一回事 完全…
You guys are really ignorant monkeys...
你們還真是一群無知的猴子啊…
Listen.
聽好了
Here is the United Kingdom of Sidelasia where our Duchy of Amonlogia belongs to.
這裡是我們阿蒙洛基亞所屬的蘇益德拉西亞聯合王國
My ship was like this... crossed the sea of sand to the west.
寡人的船像這樣…向西穿越了沙海
Then we were swallowed into a strange torrent here.
然後 在這裡被捲入奇怪的洋流
We were just about to wreck.
險些遇難
Some days after we crossed that,
通過這裡的幾天後
we landed this island.
我們就到了這座島上
So the mud whale is here!
泥鯨在這裡啊
Hey Suo! Return it!
喂 蘇澳！ 還回來！
So the island without rudder was taken by the torrent,
所以 沒有舵的這個島大概就一直順著洋流
and you were wandering in the same area for sure.
在同一片海域打轉轉吧
Exactly!
正是如此！
It's a evil sea nobody has ever been.
這是迄今為止誰都不曾靠近的魔之海域
But I crossed that dangerous area,
但寡人渡過危險海域
and found this island. What a great achievement!
發現了這座島 達成了前人未及的偉業
That's it.
是嗎…
We only know the ships of the empire
能夠以自己的意志跨越洋流的
can cross the torrent with one's own will.
迄今為止只有帝國的船
That's why the mud whale with its rudder deprived
所以被奪去舵的泥鯨
could go nowhere.
曾經哪裡都去不了
A bird in the cage...
籠中之鳥…
This sea is a natural prison.
這片大海就是天然的牢獄呢…
You were attacked by the biggest enemy of our country.
襲擊你們的 是我國最大的敵國
If you enter our bosom,
在我泱泱大國的懷抱中
we can definitely protect you, small birds in cage.
有的是地方藏幾隻嬌弱的籠中小鳥
Roharito!
羅哈里特
That country lies in the further west sea of sand.
「那個國家」 在距此更為西方的沙海之中
It's a strange country with no name.
是一個沒有名字的奇怪的國家
No name?
沒有名字？
I don't know the reason.
雖然不知道理由
But in that country, people don't have their real names.
但在「那個國家」 人民是沒有真名的…
This island is now heading for the Amonlogia in the east.
這個島現在正向東邊的阿蒙洛基亞駛去
Since you now have the rudder, you should be able to break through this torrent.
在得到了舵的如今 想必能夠突破這個洋流
Beyond that...
在前方…
A brand new world is waiting for you!
你們從未見過的世界在等待著你們
What's the case? It's already so late.
有什麼事？ 大半晚的
I have something to tell you.
我有話要說
I noticed it since the first sight.
第一次見你的時候就注意到了
Your skin has different color than those on the island.
你的膚色和這座島上的人不同
You must... from that country.
你是…「那個國家」的人吧…
What's your words? Tell me.
什麼事 說說看…
Stop looking up the people on the island.
請不要調查這座島上的人的事情…
What do you mean?
…怎麼一回事
Stop talking with them until we reach your country.
到到達你的國家為止 中斷大家的會話
No, it's impossible.
不 這是做不到的
How can we accept a short-lived clans of unknown reason?
原因不明的短命的一族 你覺得我們國家就能這麼接受了？
They may have some plague.
說不定有什麼傳染病
That's not the case.
這是沒有的
So you know the reason.
看來你知道原因啊
Hmm?
嗯？
Lykos?
…黎可斯…？
If you don't tell me what they are clearly,
不把人民的真實身份說清楚
I can't promise you to take their side.
寡人無法保證支持你們的立場
The cause is the mud whale.
原因在於泥鯨
Mud whale...
泥鯨…
You mean this ship?
這艘船是吧？
The reason why this ship as well as the ships of empire can float on the sea
這艘船和帝國的船得以浮在海面
νοῦς
νοῦς
is because a creature named Nous.
是因為一種叫魂形的生物
The Nous in my country eat the emotions of people.
我們國家的魂形 以人民的「感情」為食
sentikinesis
thymia
and give them the power of thymia in return.
作為交換給予我們「情念力」這種能力
They are called the Shirushi.
這就是 被叫做「印」的人
νοῦς
νοῦς
φάλαινα
φάλαινα
But only the Nous on the island, Fallaina, has a different role.
但是 只有這座島上的魂形「法萊那」的功能不同
Different role? What's it?
不同…？ 怎麼一回事？
Lykos...
黎可斯…
φάλαινα
φάλαινα
The food of Fallaina, and the source of Shirushi's thymia,
法萊那所食用的 作為「印」的情念力的源泉
which makes the island floating on the sea,
以及讓這座島浮在海面…
is the lives of Shirushi living on the mud whale!
是生活在泥鯨上的…
Ah...
啊…
Chakuro!
查克羅！
Wait, Chakuro!
等等 查克羅！
It's not easy.
這可不容易啊…
Hearing the bitter truth,
知曉殘酷的事實
and living without knowing the bitter truth,
和無知的活下去
no matter which you choose...
這是何其困難的選擇…
I knew it some how.
其實我多少已經察覺到了
But I pretended as I didn't know.
但是 我一直當作沒看見
I didn't want to know it.
因為一點都不想知道
So I avoided it.
所以一直在迴避著它…
Always...
一直…
Lykos.
黎可斯
We have made up our minds since you come here.
從你來到這裡的時候 我們就已經做好覺悟了
But...
…但是
It's the only thing we want to keep secret.
只有這件事不希望讓大家知道…
So the presbytery knows it...
原來長老會一直以來都知道的啊
Sorry, Suo, and everybody...
對不起啊 蘇澳 各位…
No.
不需要道歉
We will continue to support the Shirushi.
繼續支持「印」
There is no difference.
是我們不變的宗旨
That's impossible.
哼！ 這可做不到
After you get into the world outside, you will definitely notice it someday.
只要到了外面的世界 大家早晚會注意到的
Or you just stay in the cage named Fallaina?
還是說 你們打算就這樣留在法萊那這座監獄裡嗎
Hey, what's up?
喂 搞什麼啊
Start it now!
快點開始啊
Why these guys want to hole an assembly?
那兩個傢伙搞什麼集會啊
Aren't the twins the bad eggs of the internal moles?
那對雙胞胎 是體內鼴鼠裡的不良少年啊
This is made by the wings of birds shot with thymia!
這是用情念力打下的鳥的翅膀做成的！
And this is a flag made for making an oath!
而且 這是我們為宣下誓言而打造的旗幟
Under this flag, we will
在這面旗幟下 我們
form a new leader group, the rudder of purple wing!
宣布成立泥鯨新的領導人集體 「紫翼之舵」
And this is our rally!
舉行誓師大會！
We know we are not trusted by you guys!
我們知道你們不相信我們！
So we don't expect everybody's agree here!
所以也沒指望在這裡的所有人都支持我們
But since you were born,
只是 為什麼你們從出生以來
you did never doubt the system of this dolls world!
就對這個人偶一樣的世界的現狀沒有任何懷疑
This is a puzzle for us!
我們一直都搞不懂
We had been making troubles on the mud whale.
至今為止 我們一直躲在泥鯨的角落裡悶悶不樂
Because we couldn't blow the cobweb away!
也正是因為從來都沒搞明白這到底是怎麼回事
Do you guys really believe
你們之中 真有人覺得
the island is on a trip to the freedom?
這座島是向著自由的旅途前進著的嗎？
It is said that
據說泥鯨
the mud whale is heading to the country of the guys landed recently.
正向著前陣子那艘船上來的那些傢伙的國家駛去
Who decided that?
這是誰決定的！
It's not decided by you, right?
不是你們吧！
Of course not.
那自然不是啊
The decisions of this island are made by the presbytery of Muin.
因為這座島的事情都由無印的長老會來決定
Yes!
是啊
Since long long before we were born!
從我們出生之前就是這樣了！
And you think it's right.
而且 你們覺得這是正確的
Isn't it right?
這哪裡不對了
Then we'll ask you another question.
換個問法
During the recent war, how many Shirushi died?
前些時候的戰鬥 你們覺得有多少「印」死去了
I... I don't want to recall that.
…不 不想回憶啊
Why you need to ask this now?
為什麼現在要問這種問題啊
There are so many died that you don't want to recall!
因為有多到不想回憶的人死去了啊！
Hakuji from the presbytery is the only Muin died in the attack from Skulax.
斯奇洛斯的攻擊中死去的「無印」 只有長老會的哈庫奇一個
Only one!
僅僅一個人！
Remember the operation the presbytery raised that time!
想想那時候長老會安排的作戰方案！
They made trained Shirushi fight in the island.
在島上讓訓練過的印來戰鬥
And hide the Muin in the safe places of the mud whale.
無印卻躲到泥鯨裡安全的地方
We had to do that!
沒辦法啊
The Muin without thymia is no help for the fights.
讓沒有情念力的無印上戰場也沒用
Yes.
是啊
It's even more difficult to fight while protecting the Muin.
不如說讓我們一邊保護無印一邊作戰 這才是不講道理
Yes, they would be the drags on us!
是啊 他們礙手礙腳的
Yes!
對了
The Muin is exactly the drags on us!
無印本來就是「礙手礙腳」的
Don't you think it's cowardly?
不覺得他們卑鄙嗎
They are unable to use thymia, they can't do anything themselves.
沒有情念力 自己什麼都做不到
They are pieces of shit who just have long lives!
只有壽命長的窩囊廢
Such guys set the operations for their own benefits,
這些傢伙 制定對自己有利的作戰方案
and disposed of us Shirushi!
怎麼能任他們把我們印當作一次性的工具 對我們見死不救！
Didn't you ever doubt it?
難道你們迄今為止從來都沒懷疑過嗎？
You should know it!
你們也懂得的吧！
The system of the mud whale itself is a rotten cheat!
泥鯨這個組織結構本身就是陳腐虛偽的啊！
We will release us Shirushi from the dominance of Muin!
我們要把「印」從「無印」的支配之中解放出來！
We Shirushi decide where we shall go!
向何方前進應該由「印」來決定！
The ship should be ruled by us Shirushi,
這艘船應該由我們印！
by the rudder of purple wing!
由我們「紫翼之舵」來掌握實權！
Thymia is the power driving the mud whale.
情念力是泥鯨的動力
The strength of thymia decides where the mud whale go!
應該以情念力的強弱 來決定泥鯨的前進目標！
Power is everything!
力量就是一切！
We rule the mud whale?
我們來掌握泥鯨？
We go against the presbytery?
要我們反抗長老會？
Why not!
這哪裡不行了
Stop it! It is prohibited to use thymia in violence!
住手！用情念力進行暴力行為是被禁止的！
What? Isn't is a rule set by the Muin?
哼！這不也是無印設置的規則嗎
Oni!
歐尼！
Stop the meaningless violence.
不要沒意義地訴諸暴力
Even you become a dog of Muin?
連你都成了無印的忠犬了嗎
I'm on nobody's side.
我不站在任何人一邊
But you were the internal moles.
只是 你們倆過去也是體內鼴鼠
I don't like you to be this crappy.
不想看到你們這種沒有風度的樣子
Crappy?
你說我們沒有風度？
Hey what's up?
喂喂 怎麼了
You run out of power? Together with your motivation.
難道你失去力量了嗎 跟你的幹勁一起沒了
Say it Oni, you take our side.
快說啊歐尼 站在我們這邊
You are the most bloody devil in the island!
你不是這座島上
You are the strongest monster killed a number of enemies.
你不是殺了無數敵人的最強的怪物嗎
Listen, you guys!
你們也給我聽好了！
We are strong!
我們很強！
We are different from Muin!
和「無印」不一樣！
We have thymia!
我們有情念力！
乾いた海の跡　望んで
乾いた海の跡　望んで
Staring into the trace of the dried sea
眺 望 昔 日 的 大 海
With this power,
只要有這個力量
nobody will insult us, trample us again!
就沒有人再敢看扁我們 踐踏我們！
Is that true?
是這樣嗎…
まだ見ぬ対岸を描く
まだ見ぬ対岸を描く
I will draw the other side I have never seen
描 繪 未 知 的 彼 岸
No, that's impossible.
描 繪 未 知 的 彼 岸
Hey, Oni.
啊 歐尼
Let's show you the power of us.
讓你見識見識我們的力量吧
囚われの心のままなら
囚われの心のままなら
If you remain your heart in captivity
如 果 囚 禁 起 心 靈 一 如 過 往
We will live strongly and freely.
強大而自由的生活下去…
κόκαλο
κόκαλο
The rudder named Kókkalo.
名為骨頭的舵
こんな傷みも知らずにいた
こんな傷みも知らずにいた
You may live without knowing the pain
又 怎 會 經 歷 如 此 悲 傷
And the freedom available from the rudder.
名為舵的自由
Though we have found more possibilities,
雖然我們發現了新的可能
the mud whale lost its destination
但泥鯨卻失去了前進的方向
美しい詞を告げたひと
美しい詞を告げたひと
The one who told the beautiful story
是 誰 講 述 起 美 好 的 希 望
and started to wander.
開始彷徨
The yoke of the truth of our short-lives,
短命的真相這一桎梏
was pressing me...
將我沉沉鎖住…
The eleventh section
第 十 一 節
Something about the dream
第 十 一 節
夜明けも待たずに
夜明けも待たずに
Can not wait for the dawn
讓我等不及黎明
果てのその先を泳ぐ
果てのその先を泳ぐ
Until beyond the end of world, I am swimming
向著天涯海角揚帆起航
虫の唄
虫の唄
Listen to the insects' song
徹夜蟲鳴
眠らず君と聞いた記憶
眠らず君と聞いた記憶
That night is our memory
回憶裡與你一起側耳傾聽
手を　ただ結んで
手を　ただ結んで
Just link hand in hand
只是雙手相牽
半色でも　遠い国でも
半色でも　遠い国でも
No matter it is twilight or a distant country
不論夕陽  還是遠方
短い一章に生まれた夢を
短い一章に生まれた夢を
Born in a short chapter
在這短暫蒼渺的一章裡
抱きしめに行こう
抱きしめに行こう
But let us go and embrace that dream
一起追逐夢想
The final section
最 終 節
It is great I was born here
生 在 這 裡 真 是 太 好 了